tempur.com 2012-06-14

# Privacy policy | Tempur-Pedic

At Tempur-Pedic, we are committed to protecting your privacy and making it clear how we use your information. This privacy policy describes the kinds of information that we may collect about you; how we use that information; how we protect it; when we disclose it; and how you can access and control your information.

## Your consent

By visiting our website, by requesting an information kit or other product detail, or by purchasing products directly from us (either on our website or by phone) you are indicating that you agree to these policies.

## Information we collect

There are three kinds of information we collect: “personal information“, “credit information“ and “non-personal“. There’s a difference in how we treat each type of information.

### Personal information

Personal information includes your name, address (both billing and shipping addresses), e-mail address credit card information, phone number and information about the products you purchase from us. We share your name, billing address, phone number and the products you purchase with the vendors we use to process your order and ship the products to you. We share your credit card information with the vendors who process the credit card purchase. We use your shipping address to ship your products to you and to send catalogs and other mailings to you. We use your billing address to verify your billing information. If you don’t want to receive mailings from us, please see the "How to control your information" section below.

### Credit information

Credit information is the information we use if you apply for financing through us. When you apply for Tempur-Pedic Financing or an alternative form of financing that we may offer, we pass your personal information directly to the bank(s) administering that account for us. We don’t store the information on our servers: rather we send it to the administering bank. Except for the bank(s) administering the lines of credit, we do not share your credit information either internally or externally with anyone else. Please note that “credit information“ as described in this paragraph is not the same as “credit card information“, which is part of your personal information.

### Non-personal information

Non-personal information includes the pages you visit on our website, how many clicks it takes to reach specific information, and the kinds of purchases you make on our site. This data is in an anonymous format and doesn’t contain any personal information about you. We share non-personal information about your website visits with vendors who help us administer our website or help us market our products.

### When we collect your information

We collect information from you when you visit the site and when you do business with us.

### When ordering and making a purchase

When you place an order with us, either using our website or by phone, we collect your personal information. This includes your name, shipping and billing addresses, e-mail address, phone number, credit card information, and the details of your order. We collect such personal information to process your order, including collecting payment and shipping products to you.

### When creating an online account

When you set up an online shopping account, we collect your personal information. This includes your name, shipping and billing addresses and e-mail address. We collect such personal information to simplify doing business with us by retaining your information for return visits to our website.

### When signing up for promotional mail and e-mail

When you sign up for promotional mail and e-mails or request a product information kit from us, we may collect your personal information. This may include your name, mailing address and e-mail address. We collect such personal information so we can send you product information and notice of special promotions.

### When registering a product

When you register a Tempur-Pedic product with us, we collect your personal information. If you bought the product directly from us, we have your basic personal information, but we collect information about the specific item you purchased, including information like the serial number. We also optionally collect personal preference information, which includes questions about your household and your purchase decision. We collect personal preference information because it helps us in developing new products and marketing that meet consumers’ needs.

### When contributing to our website

When you submit product reviews, product testimonials, or other content to our website, we collect some personal information. This may include your name and e-mail address. We collect personal information because it helps us ensure we are giving accurate and authentic feedback about our products.

### When visiting our website

When you visit our website, we collect non-personal information about your visit. This includes information about your Internet service provider, the type of computer and web browser you are using, and the pages you click on when you visit the site. We collect non-personal information because it helps us to keep our site working properly with the many types of computers and browsers people use to view our site, and because knowing this information helps us to determine which information on our site is most valuable to people who visit.

### How we collect information

We collect information in three ways: when you give us your information during checkout (on our website or over the phone) or using one of the forms on our website, when you visit our website and click through the pages, and when we collect information from other sources (such as information kit requests and calls to our 1-800 Number).

### Information you give us

When you purchase a product from us, either on our website or by phone, we ask you for personal information so we can complete your order. We also collect personal information when you set up an online shopping account, sign up for promotional mail or e-mail, and when you call us to request an information kit or to learn about products. The personal information that you give us may be combined with other personal information (such as order history and demographic information) from third-party sources to make our marketing efforts more efficient.

### Information we collect when you visit our website

When you visit our website, we collect non-personal information about your visit using common website tracking technologies. These include your Internet Protocol ("IP") address, “cookies“, and action tags.

IP address is the number automatically assigned to your computer whenever you access the Internet that we use to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our website; this number does not identify your name, email address, or other personal information.

Cookies are computer files that act as an identification card for your computer. When you visit our site, unique cookies are placed on your browser. The purpose of the cookie is to distinguish your browser from other browsers that visit our site. Cookies make it easier for you to use our website. We use a cookie in order to remember the products in your shopping cart, both while you are viewing other areas on our website and when you return to our site. We also use cookies to gather aggregate usage information about the numbers and frequency of visitors to our website and individual pages of our website, in order to improve the appearance and usability of the website. Working through our third party digital advertising agency (along with its ad serving technology partner and several partnered networks of publishers) we also use cookies to track your interests and then provide you with customized banner ads that we think will be more useful because they are based on past purchase and page visits to our site. These cookies do not collect personal information about you, nor do we combine information collected through these cookies with other personal information about you. Cookies may remain on your hard drive after you leave our website. You may decline to accept cookies by modifying your Web browser settings. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to sign up for or use certain features of the website that depend on your Web browser accepting cookies (such as keeping products in your cart).

Action Tags recognize specific cookies that have been placed on your browser by us and by networks of publishers that are partnered with our digital advertising agency. They can convey information that a browser with a recognized cookie has accessed a page or a part of a page on our website, depending on where the action tag is located on our site. For instance, an action tag located on our purchase confirmation page will record that a browser with a recognized cookie has made a purchase. Action tags do not, however, tell us that a specific person has purchased a product because the cookie is only the web browser’s identification card. It does not obtain any Personally Identifiable Information. We use Action Tags to measure the effectiveness of our digital advertising campaign and to make our website more relevant to visitors by seeing what pages are visited and whether visits result in a purchase. Action Tags also allow our digital advertising agency to select and serve banner advertisements to your browser that you find most interesting and relevant.

### Information we collect from other sources

When you sign up for catalogs from companies, many of those companies share your personal information with trusted partners who will also send you catalogs. We belong to a group of companies, all of them screened for their business practices, which share the names and addresses of people who agree to receive our printed catalogs. We may receive other information from these sources including updated delivery and address information, which we use to correct our records and deliver catalogs and promotions accurately.

### How to control your information

After you give us your personal information, you can access and check, add, change or remove the information we have on file for you.

### Adding your name to our lists

If you haven’t ordered from us, but want to receive catalogs or e-mails from us, you can add your name to our mailing lists. You can receive printed catalogs, e-mails, or both. We use our mailing lists to send notice of new products and special offers. Add your name to our lists [here](http://www.tempurpedic.com/customer-service/contact-preferences.asp).

### Removing your name from our lists

If you decide you don’t want to receive mailings from us, you can remove your name from our mailing lists. You can stop receiving printed mailings, e-mails, or both. Remove your name from our lists [here](http://www.tempurpedic.com/customer-service/contact-preferences.asp).

### Changing the information we have on file

If your personal information changes (like when you move), you can change the information we have on file for you.Change your personal information [here](http://www.tempurpedic.com/customer-service/contact-preferences.asp).

### Accessing your personal information

You may contact us (see contact details below) to check what personal information we have on file for you. To protect your personal information against unauthorized disclosure, we will ask you to appropriately identify yourself before responding to your inquiries.

You can also contact us by phone, e-mail or mail to add, remove or change your information:

Phone: 800-821-6621 (Customer Service)  
E-mail: customer.service@tempurpedic.com  
Mail: Tempur-Pedic, Customer Service, 1713 Jaggie Fox Way, Lexington, KY 40511

## Sharing your information

### Social networking

We offer you the opportunity to share information about our products and our website using “share this“ functionality. We offer this functionality in order to generate interest in our products among the members of your social networks and to permit you to share opinions and recommendations about our products with your friends. Sharing either personal or non-personal information with a social network may result in that information being collected by the social network hosting company or may result in that information being made public.

### Service providers

We employ other companies and individuals to perform certain services and functions on our behalf. These include operating and maintaining our website, taking orders, delivering packages, sending postal mail and e-mail, removing repetitive information from customer lists, analyzing data, providing marketing consultation and assistance, distributing customer surveys, processing credit card payments, and providing customer service. These companies have access to the personal information needed to perform their services or functions, but may not use it for other purposes.

We also work with third parties to serve advertisements about our company across the web. These third parties my use tracking technologies (described under “How We Collect Information“ above) to collect anonymous data about users who view or interact with advertisements on our website. We do not provide any personal information about the users to these third parties. However, by interacting with, viewing, or clicking on an ad or visiting our website, the third party might collect non-personally identifiable information about you like an anonymous cookie ID, the specific ad posted on the site, and the place and time of ad delivery. Third parties may use tracking technologies, such as cookies and action tags when serving ads. These commonly used technologies are used for auditing, research, and reporting purposes. Third party cookies and action tags are subject to the privacy policy of the company placing them. For information about opting out of third party cookies, you may visit the Network Advertising Initiative at [www.networkadvertsing.org](http://www.networkadvertsing.org/).

### For your protection and ours

We may release personal information when we believe it is appropriate to comply with applicable law regulation, legal process, or governmental request; enforce or apply our Terms of Use and other agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of Tempur-Pedic, our customers, our employees or others.

### Business transfer

As we develop our business, we might sell or buy subsidiaries or business units. In such transactions, customer information generally is one of the transferred business assets but remains subject to the promises made in any pre-existing privacy policy (unless, of course, the customer consents otherwise). Also, in the unlikely event that Tempur-Pedic or substantially all of its assets are acquired, customer information will be one of the transferred assets.

### Sharing

We may share your name and mailing address with other reputable companies so they may send you catalogs about products of potential interest. We only share your name and address; we do not share your e-mail address, credit card information or information about the purchases you make from us.

## How we protect your personal information

We want you to feel confident about using our website or making purchases directly from us, and we are committed to protecting the personal information we collect. We have implemented appropriate physical, electronic, administrative and organizational security measures to protect the personal information that you provide to us against unauthorized access or disclosure. Our security system includes protocols to authenticate users and to restrict access. If we transmit personal information across public networks and wirelessly, the data will be encrypted.

In the unlikely event that your personal information is accessed without authorization or disclosed to unauthorized individuals, we will promptly comply with any data breach notification requirements imposed under applicable law.

### Children's privacy

We do not knowingly sell merchandise to or direct advertising toward persons under 13 years of age (“children“). We do not knowingly collect any PII from children.

### Links to external websites

If any part of our website links you to other websites, those websites do not operate under this privacy policy. We recommend that you examine the privacy statements posted on those other websites to understand their procedures for collecting, using, and disclosing personal information.

## Changes to this policy

We may update this policy in the future. We will post at the top of this Privacy Policy the date on which it was most recently updated.

## How to contact us

If you have questions about our privacy policy or the privacy and security of your information, you can contact us in one of the following ways:

E-mail: [privacy.compliance@tempurpedic.com](mailto:privacy.compliance@tempurpedic.com)  
Mail: Tempur-Pedic, Privacy Compliance, 1713 Jaggie Fox Way, Lexington, KY 40511
